Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania 1705-1788 Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania
1705-1788
Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Benjamin Franklin Papers (Mss B F85). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description. The materials listed here are not held at the APS.
767 items
Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Charles Pemberton Fox, 1840.
The materials in this collection were originally part of the collection bequeathed by Benjamin Franklin to his grandson, William Temple Franklin, and then given to George Fox. When the bulk of that collection was donated to the American Philosophical Society, some manuscripts were left behind at the Fox estate, Champlost, and these were subsequently donated to the University of Pennsylvania.
- Correspondence (University of Pennsylvania), 1758-1788
  Scope and Contents note
  The materials that comprise the University of Pennsylvania's Benjamin Franklin Papers are concentrated in the period of the American Revolution, documenting Franklin's ministry in France, the progress of the American Revolution and French participation, and Franklin's personal affairs in France.
  The organization of the collection is essentially chronological, however there are three discrete chronological sequences. The item listing below is derived from I. Minis Hays's calendar of the Franklin Papers without emendation.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Mrs. Deane, Mrs. London
    Acknowledging the copy of [Poor] Richard's Maxims, which are so excellent that they ought to be framed and hung up in every house.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1761 July 24; Printed N.S. Peter Templeman, Secretary. 1p.; The Society for the Encouragement of Arts, etc. London
    Notice of a Committee meeting to consider further the subject of Ship's Blocks.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1761 December 31; A.N. in 3d P. 1p.; Ralph. Miss. London
    Her father [James Ralph] out of danger, but still very weak. Compliments to Mrs. [Margaret] Stevenson.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1762 February 25; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Mead, Mr. London
    Account of the good effects of electricity, sent by a curate of Dr. Douglass, which Lord Bath wished he might see; desires to know if Dr. Franklin has anything to add to it before publication.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1762 December 18; A.L.S. 1p.; Walker, Hannah. Westbury
    Glad to hear of his safe arrival in London.
  - Appendix, 1764 December 24; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Todd, Anthony. London
    Desiring an interview to show him the proposed clauses for the intended Act of Parliament.
  - Appendix, 1765 June 27; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Neale,William. St. Maryhill
    Promising to send his carriage to convey him and Mrs. [Margaret] Stevenson to Richmond.
  - Appendix, [1765.] July 17; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Charles, Robert. London
    Desiring his company at the "Letter Feast," at the King's Arms Tavern, Cornhill.
  - Appendix, 1765 July 18; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Todd, Anthony. London
    Announcing that Lord Bessborough and Lord Grantham will meet at the [General Post] Office at noon to open their patent.
  - Appendix, A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Denny, Colonel
    Invitation to dinner at the Star and Garter, Pall Mall, at a crown a head.
  - Appendix, A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Michell, John. London
    Invitation to dinner.
  - Appendix, 1767 July 21; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Sherwood, Joseph. London
    Concerning [apparently a land claim] which he is attending to for Dr. Franklin.
  - Appendix, A.L.S. 1p.; Hope, Messrs. Amsterdam
  - Appendix, 1768 January 21; A.L.S. 2p.; Whitefield, George. London
    Desiring another interview. The College affair lies dormant. Prophesies the destruction of the world; hopes they will be among the happy few saved.
  - Appendix, A.N. in 3d P. 1p.; Pownall, Thomas. London
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Saunders, Dr. Richard Huck
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 October 12; A.L.S. 1p.; Galloway, Joseph. Philadelphia
    Introducing Jacob Rush, brother of Dr. [Benjamin] Rush, who desires to complete his law studies at the Temple.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1770 October 14; A.L.S. 2p.; Rush, Benjamin. Philadelphia
    Introducing his brother [Jacob Rush] who intends to study for two years in the Temple, London, in order to finish his studies in the law.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 February 12; L.S. 1p.; Sherwood, Joseph. London
    Desiring dates and particulars in the boundary dispute between the Penns and Lord Baltimore.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 March 20; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Jennings, Miss. London
    Sending him a catalogue of the articles desired by herself and M. Conway.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 May 20; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Jackson, Richard. London, General Post Office
    Sending him a piece of elastic gum.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, L. in 3d P. 1p.; Montagu, George. Duke of Manchester
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1771; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Walsh, John. London
    Desiring Mr. [Edward] Bancroft's address; wishes to make inquiries concerning the "torporifick eel."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, N. in 3d P. 1p.; Mr. and Mrs. William Hewson
    Reminding him of his promise to dine with them.
  - Appendix, 1772 May; Engraved N. 1p.; The Associates of the Late Dr. Bray for Founding Libraries, and Instructing the Negroes in the British Plantations. London
    Invitation to dinner at the King's Head Tavern, Holborn, on May 21.
  - Appendix, A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Shipley, Jonathan
    Will wait upon him the following evening with his family and Lord and Lady Spencer.
  - Appendix, 1774 June; Engraved N. 1p.; Heberden, Dr. William. London
    Invitation to dinner on June 10.
  - Appendix, A.L.S. 1p.; Collinson, Peter
    Enjoyed his "Vindication [and offer from Congress to Parliament]" very much; it must morrify [Chief Justice William] Allen, for it cuts him to the quick; wishes a copy sent to David Barday, Jr.
  - Appendix, 1776 July 5; D.S. Count de Azambuja, Pres[ident]. 2p.; The King of Portugal. Lisbon
    An edict prohibiting all intercourse between his dominions and the Rebel American Colonies.
    (Copy. Translated into English.)
  - Appendix, 1776 July 11; A.L.S. 2p.; Jones, Nobel Wimberly. Savannah
    Prevented by his father's death and his own illness, from sitting in the Continental Congress. The South not as well prepared for defense as the North; Georgia's need of assistance. Indian massacres.
  - Appendix, 1776 October 3; A.L.S. 4p.; Wayne, Anthony. Ticonderoga
    Pleased to hear of the unanimity prevailing in Congress and of the settlement of the boundaries of the various States; glad the Convention is engaged in founding a new Government; surprised at the evacuation of Long Island. Situation of the Americans on Lake Champlain strength of the British; condition of his brigade. Question of enlistments.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776 October 28; A.L.S. 1p.; Sparre, [J.] de. Strasbourg
    Offering to come to Paris if he can be of any use.
    (In French.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776 December 23; D.S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y, John Hancock, Presid[en]t. 2p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolved that the American Commissioners to France, furnish exact information as to Portugal's attitude towards America; orders to fit out vessels to prey upon British property; concerning a loan of 2,000,000 sterling.
    Bibliography
    Printed in Journals of Continental Congress, VI, 1035, Washington, 1906.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 January 1; L.S. Benj[amin] Harrison, Richard Henry Lee, Jno. Witherspoon, Will[iam] Hooper. 1p.; The Continental Congress, Committee of Secret Correspondence. Baltimore
    Announcing his appointment, by Congress, as their Commissioner to negotiate a Treaty of Friendship and Commerce with the Court of Spain.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 January 18; A.L.S. 1p.; de Rullecour, Baron. Paris
    Offers for his use a vessel of 64 guns which can be ready to sail in a fortnight; makes a similar offer for the month of May.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 January 20; A.L.S. 2p.; de Rullecour, Baron. Paris
    Concerning the offer of a vessel to transport goods to America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 January; A.L.S. 1p.; Gruel, J
    Account of monies paid by him.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 February 28; A.L.S. 2p.; Sparre, [J.] de. Strasbourg
    Concering the raising of troops in Hesse; can secure surgeons for the American army, if desired.
  - Appendix, 1777 May 12; D.S. 2p.; Lee, Arthur. Paris
    Giving Dr. Franklin power of attorney to transact all business for him in Paris.
  - Appendix, 1777 July 4; A.L.S. 1p.; d'Aurouer, Madame Carroll
    Desires a personal interview.
  - Appendix, 1777 May 1 to August 6; 48p.; Pillet, -----
    Bills of household expenses, receipted.
  - Appendix, 1777 August 25; L. 2p.; ------, ------. St. Eustache
    Evacuation of Ticonderoga; [Gen. Arthur] St. Clair and [Gen. Mathieu Alexis de] Rochefermoy blamed. Howe's probable destination. [Gen. Robert] Prescott replaced in Rhode Island by [Gen. Sir Robert] Pigot.
  - Appendix, 1777 October 27; A.L.S. 1p.; d'Hanache, Marquis Alexandre. Paris
    Enclosing a letter for the Comte de Stirling [William Alexander Lord Stirling].
  - Appendix, 1777 December 14; A.L.S. 3p.; Ingenhousz, Jan
    Has leave of absence to go to Holland and England; desires some political news which may serve to keep his Royal Mistress in good humor. Reflections on the American revolt and England's probable attitude.
  - Appendix, 1777 December 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Deane, Silas. Passy
    Does not fully understand the enclosed; has gone to consult M. [Conrad Alexandre] Gérard [de Rayneval] about it.
  - Appendix, [1777.]; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Mercier, -----
    Desiring payment for his work of repairing arms.
  - Appendix, [1777.]; A.L.S. 1p.; Mercier, -----
    Begs for a reply to the two petitions he has had the honor of presenting.
  - to The American Commissioners., [1777.]; L.S. 2p.; Mercier, -----
    Appeal for payment for the work of repairing muskets.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1777.]; L. 1p.; -----, -----
    Defending Mr. [William] Hodge and requesting his release; [Capt. Gustavus] Conyngham alone to blame.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, L. 2p.; -----, -----
    Desires employment in America as military engineer; need of secrecy in his case.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 January 3; A.L.S. 2p.; Hutton, James. Passy
    Begging him as an humane man to write to his friends in Pennsylvania to use their influence to prevent unauthorized attacks upon Bethlehem; account of an attack made on the village which was repulsed by convalescent soldiers who were in the military hospital, and of another in which they dragged a man at a horse's tail from Bethlehem to Easton.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 January 31; A.L.S. 5p.; Bache, Richard. Manheim
    Account of their flight before the British advance at the time of the battle of Brandywine. His wife gave birth to a daughter. Franklin's printing press sold to the State of Virginia. Acknowledges the receipt of the engraver's and potter's performances. The engraver he thinks has paid more attention to the fur cap than to the lines of the face. Theft of a package addressed by Franklin to Congress. Concerning the newspapers then being published. Family affairs.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 February 9; A.L.S. 2p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul. Nantes
    News from America; situation of [Gen.] Washington's and [Sir William] Howe's armies; Jersey militia sent to protect their own country; [Gen.] Burgoyne at Winter Hill; reinforcements for Washington; fall of Howe determined; American army in fine spirits; Continental money appreciating; many prizes brought in; Generals [Horatio] Gates and [Israel] Putnam in command at King's Bridge; [Gen. Sir Henry] Clinton in possession of no post beyond that point.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 4; A.L.S. 3p.; Knoepffelius, Andrew Christian. Nordshausen
    Desiring the position of Pastor at the German Reformed Church in Philadelphia; offers to come to Paris to see Dr. Franklin.
    (In Latin.)
  - Appendix, 1778 March 10; A.L.S. 1p.; O'Gorman, Thomas, chevalier
    Stating the amount of Dr. Franklin's debt for the rental of a carriage, and for wine used on the journey.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 12; Printed D. 1p.; De Bescheloche, -----. Saint-Aubin
    Bill of duties paid on wine.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 13; Printed D. 1p.; Moreau, -----
    Receipt of duties paid on wine.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 18; A.L.S. 3p.; L'Espagne, -----. Paris
    Lost his fortune in a law-suit; sends Dr. Franklin a book he has written; if he can be of use to the young American Pepublic, offers to emigrate there with his son and daughter.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 24; A.L.S. 3p.; de Hari, Mechia Caph. Bienne
    In spite of his parents' objections, desires to enter the American army; desires Dr. Franklin's aid.
  - Appendix, 1778 March 25; A.L.S. 2p.; Wren, Thomas. Portsmouth
    Writes on behalf of the prisoners, who desire a certain sum per week granted them for food; extortionate charges made by the person who furnishes their meals.
  - Appendix, 1778 April 2; A.L.S. 3p.; fils, Gautier. Au Cap François
    Concerning a claim by a man called [Stephen] Ceronio, to be an Agent of Congress; if true, his inability to pay a certain debt reflects upon his Government.
  - Appendix, 1778 April 9; A.L.S. 1p.; L'Allemand, Madame
    Sending a letter for him, committed to her care.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 April 9; A.L.S. 4p.; D'Espagne, -----. Paris
    Desiring the position of French Consul in America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 April 10; A.L.S. 2p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    Sends the pretended reply of Great Britain to the Declaration of Independence; too long and erroneous to print; glad to publish any refutation Dr. Franklin may care to prepare.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 April 18; A.L.S. 1p.; Melmoth, Courtney. Paris
    Prevented by sudden business from waiting on him with Mrs. Melmoth.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 April 21; L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Laumoy, Madame. Orleans
    Asking for news of her son, who entered the American service in June, 1776.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 April 23; A.L.S. 1p.; Schweighauser, John D. Nantes
    Introducing his son-in-law, M. Dobrée.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 1; A.L.S. 1p.; Williams, John
    Has been shamefully and designedly deceived; refers Dr. Franklin, for details, to the bearer, Dr. [James] Smith, well-known for his loyalty to America. His own imminent departure.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 5; A.L.S. 2p.; de Lugny, -----. Bordeaux
    As an experienced military engineer, desires to go to America and serve in the army.
  - to The American Commissioners., 1778 May 6; A.L.S. 3p.; fils, ------- Martin. Marseilles
    Desiring recommendations to merchants in the principal American ports, where he expects to sell his cargoes.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 8; A.L.S. 1p.; La Chesnaÿe, Glèyo. L'Orient
    About to sail for America; offers his services.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 8; A.L.S. 1p.; Feutry, Aimé Ambroise Joseph
    Sending a work of his which is out of print; expects to meet him at M. [Le Ray] de Chaumont's dinner; begs for a recommendation to Madame de Thélusson; desires her support for a certain petition.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 9; A.L.S. 4p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    Promising to use the Resolution of Congress of December 19th. Sends a list of eleven ships, ordered by the British to watch the movements of the French. Arrival of important dispatches at St. James's [Palace, London] from France on May 3d, which were immediately sent to the King, at Portsmouth.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 10; A.L.S. 2p.; de Lameth, Comtesse de Eroglie. Dourier
    Writes on behalf of the Chevalier de Bazantin, who was captured by the English on his way to join the American troops; asks that he may be exchanged and given a position worthy of his talents.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 13; A.L.S. 2p.; Cushing, Thomas. Boston
    Rejoices with him over the consummation of the two treaties with France; while still ignorant of this alliance, Congress passed resolutions which did them much honor. Acknowledging his kindness to the writer's son [Thomas Cushing, Jr.,] now in France.
    (In duplicate.)
  - Appendix, 1778 May 13; A.L.S. 2p.; Cooper, Samuel. Boston
    Congratulates him upon the consummation of the French treaties; gave public thanks from his pulpit; before this alliance was known, Congress had done itself much honor by its spirited rejection of Lord Howe's peace proposals.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 14; A.L.S. 2p.; Cooper, Samuel. Boston
    Joy in America over the news of the French treaties. Glowing prophesies of what a French fleet in the Delaware could accomplish.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 14; A.L.S. 3p.; Carmichael, William. Boston
    Arrival of the "Deane" on May Ist, also the two ships loaded by Mr. [John] Ross on account of Congress; the country rejoiced over the French Alliance; expense incurred through the late arrival of the clothing. Distress caused by the depreciation of paper money. Incidents of his voyage; difficulties and expense of travelling. Size of American army. High esteem in which [Marquis de] la Fayette, Count Pulaski, Chevalier de Bertail and Gen. [Thomas] Conway are held.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 15; A.L.S. 3p.; Lovell, James. York
    His letter concerning Mr. [Silas] D[eane] read in Congress; reasons why Congress regarded Deane's recall as imperative; his services not underestimated; believes he may return with honor, on a mission to Holland.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 18; A.L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Promising, as far as possible, to avoid any dispute with Mr. [William] Lee's deputy. Encloses a letter from Lieut. [Thomas] Simpson, who is under arrest and wishes to be sent to America for trial.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 19; A.L.S. 3p.; La Blancherie, Claude-Mammès de Pahin Champlain de
    Soliciting his support for the plan he intends presenting to the Academy on the morrow.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 22; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Duperon, Anisson. Paris
    Reminding him of his promise to dine with him and visit the Royal Printing office.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 22; A.L.S. 1p.; Allaire, Peter. Calais
    Just arrived from England; all the fleet in the Downs under way; the twelve ships of the line at St. Helen's have probably sailed too.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 May 23; A.L.S. 2p.; de Brancas, Lowendal Comtesse. Paris
    Desires to enlist his interest in behalf of [the Chevalier d'Abezac,] a young French Corporal who wishes to serve in the American army.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 25; A.L.S. 2p.; Charles Grant, Le Vicomte de Vaux. Paris
    Desiring to know if the two vessels the "Lion" and "de Vaux" are among the number taken by the English.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 26; L. in 3d P. 2p.; Turgot,------
    Desiring letters of introduction to prominent people in Charleston, for M. Roulhac who intends to establish a commercial house in that city; withdrawing his previous request for letters for M. [Menedrieu] de Barcis.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 26; A.L.S. 1p.; Barbeu-Dubourg, -----
    Enclosing a letter from M. [Thomas François] Busson, recommended to Dr. Franklin by M. Dalibard. Question whether hernia, especially umbillical hernia, is as common in America as it is in Europe; advisability of sending samples of bandages of trusses.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 27; L.S. 5p.; Cazeneuve, Jerome. Bordeaux
    Account of a projected meeting on board the "Boston," to betray the frigate; with the consent of the Captain, he acted as a spy upon the conspirators.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 27; A.L.S. 3p.; La Blancherie, Claude-Mammès de Pahin Champlain de
    Entreats Dr. Franklin to be present at the meeting of the Académie des Sciences, as he fears some hostile action on the part of his enemies, which would destroy the work of years.
  - Appendix, 1778 May 29; A.L.S. 3p.; Duran, L. St. Affrique
    Desiring information for the use of serveral young Frenchmen who intend going into business in America.
  - Appendix, 1778 May; A.L. 2p.; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste
    Requesting a letter of recommendation for a rich and worthy merchant of Bretagne, M. Lalande Robinot, who is ready to send a vessel to America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 1; A.L.S. 1p.; Borel, A
    Desiring him to appoint a time when he may make his portrait.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 1; A.L.S. 4p.; Cooper, Samuel. Boston
    Public honors paid to France. Conciliatory proposals by the British; at the same time they made a barbarous attack upon Bristol; rumored that the British are to leave Philadelphia. Spirit in the American army. Burgoyne tried by court-martial, a favor he did not deserve. The proposed Constitution rejected; reasons for this. Mr. [John] Adams sailed for France in February; the ship reported captured.
    (A. Copy.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 1; A.L.S. 3p.; de Brétigney, Chevalier. Cap François
    Free again after six months in a British prison; expects to serve in the Georgia troops under the command of one of his friends. Glad to learn of the Franco-American Alliance.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 2; A.L.S. 3p.; de Rochefermoy, ------. Nancy
    Report circulated by the Gazette of Leyden that the American officers at Ticonderoga were bribed by the British; as this reflects severely on his father [Mathieu-Alexis de Rochefermoy], Brigadier-General at Ticonderoga, begs Dr. Franklin to deny the report.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 5; A.L.S. 1p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    Hears that he has received a bundle of newspapers from America; will be glad to translate and print any extracts he may deem desirable.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 8; A.L.S. 1p.; de St. Montant, -----. Paris
    Requesting an interview.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 10; A.L.S. 2p.; Desnos, -----
    Desires to enter the American army; asks for a free passage.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 14; A.L.S. 1p.; Mesny, -----. Roquancourt
    Supporting a petition of Madame de Poulinet de Besançon; particular interest taken by M. de la Faye in the lady.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 15; A.L.S. 3p.; Hartmann, Rudolphe Ernest. Amsterdam
    Requesting information about Baron Hermann de Zedewitz, who stole a quantity of gems from the writer, in London, and then fled to America; Zedwirz's subsequent career in the American army; since May, 1777, has heard nothing of him.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 17; A.L.S. 1p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    Desiring him to reply to an English attack on the Declaration of Independence; if he is too busy, will write it himself.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 17; A.L.S. 2p.; La Blancherie, Claude-Mammès de Pahin Champlain de
    Desiring his presence at the Academy to see the model of a piece of sculpture relating to North America.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 17; A.L.S. 2p.; Lainneville, -----. Brest
    Sends a package and letters received for him at Boston; refers him to them for American news.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 19; A.L.S. 2p.; Delos, -----. Strasbourg
    The Government unable to co-operate with [Capt. Jacques] Le Maire, purchasing agent for the United States, without a letter from the Minister of War. Recommending a young officer, M. Marcellin, for a position in the American army.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 20; A.L.S. 2p.; Huerne P. Paris
    Desiring to go to America, under his patronage.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 20; A.L.S. 3p.; Magellan, Jean-Hyacinthe de. Paris
    About to leave [for London]; good wishes for Dr. Franklin's welfare and for the glorious cause. Praise for the President de Saron and all his family.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 24; A.L.S. 2p.; Bouget, A. Morat